Contact

nash.surapureddy@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/nashreddy4 (LinkedIn) nash1983.github.io/Portfolio/ (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Terraform
Microsoft SQL Server
Internet Information Services (IIS)

Languages

Hindi (Elementary)
English (Professional Working)
Telugu (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

MCTS SQL 2008 Implementation and Maintenance

Honors-Awards

Best Employee Award Information Systems Security (INFOSEC) Professional

Best Customer Service Award / Smile Award

Nash Reddy

Application Analyst - Bolton Clarke Brisbane City, Queensland, Australia

Summary

An experienced professional with a solid background in devising IT solutions for improved business efficiency. Highly focused on end user satisfaction through quality delivery of services. I thrive working in a fast pace environment that requires problem solving, implementing new ideas and delivering enhanced customer experience.

Experience

Bolton Clarke
Application Analyst
December 2018 - Present (3 years 10 months)
Australia

Perform analysis of existing application protocols and software tools.

Hands on experience on Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, CI/CD, Terraform,

Prometheus and Grafana Dashboards.

Developed automation processes using Python to reduce extensive manual processing to a short automated process.

Design and develop a new application architecture that supports business growth.

Provide and support recommendations for improved procedures and policies.

Provide application support in resolving and troubleshooting problems.

Assist and support in achieving departmental goals and objectives.

Provide advanced application support to utilise the system infrastructure and resources effectively.

Provide direct assistance to users in using and interpreting software tools and products.

Interact with software vendors to provide the best solutions to business problems.

Provide application support to other internal users and developers in handling multiple projects.

Ensure compliance with all security measures in application development processes.

Plan and implement application releases. In addition, I work with vendors and business stakeholders to evaluate new releases and guide the testing approach.

Ensure non-prod environments are configured and maintained systematically to conserve the integrity of the testing processes.

Provide data extraction and high-quality analysis on an ad-hoc basis to help inform critical business decisions and metrics.

Propose, Plan and Deliver changes efficiently by following ITIL methodologies, outlining potential risks and impacts on the user

MVP Studio - Uptown Innovation Software Developer June 2018 - November 2018 (6 months) Australia

MVP Studio is an incubator for software start-ups.

I worked on a Keys project, an Automated, Intelligent property investment platform.

Worked on C#, ASP.NET MVC, JIRA, HTML/JavaScript/React/CSS/ jQuery, SQL2012

Involved in Daily Stand-up meetings,

Involved in Keys project feasibility study and provided technical solutions.

I created a page that appears when a Tenant signs up for the first time. It has a form that gets the tenant's personal information.

Involved in project Sprints and completed assigned tasks.

Having experience in SDLC and Agile work environments

AIA

4 years 4 months

IT Production Controller January 2016 - April 2018 (2 years 4 months) New Zealand

- Experienced in the implementation of small, medium and large projects on .Net & SQL Technologies
- Experienced in installing, maintaining and monitoring Windows servers and applications on-premises
- · performed server hardening and house-keeping
- Performed SQL database administration such as backup, restoration and truncation
- Administered backup tapes and rotated as required

- Expertise in operational support and maintenance of business-critical inhouse applications with a high focus on quality and efficiency improvement
- Had experience in SDLC and Agile work environments
- Involved in feasible project study and provided technical solutions.
 Completed several end-to-end projects
- Maintain high system availability and distribute the reports to users promptly
- Perform file backup and restore operation following client requirements, mapping network shared drives and maintaining AD security groups.
- Prepare and implement system and security patches.
- Promote the software releases to a Production environment
- Administration of the AS400 Environment, including capacity, job scheduling and availability
- Coordinate with Application services and vendors in resolving technical/ application problems and changes in the operating environment
- System monitoring and house-keeping
- On call for nightly cycle runs
- Carry out job recovery & special processing requests such as SPRR, PTRR, Restoration, Backup
- · Maintain accurate document and record control
- Maintain Technical and compliance IT documentation as required, Giving IT induction training to new starters and basic training on Microsoft products.

IT Systems Analyst

January 2014 - January 2016 (2 years 1 month)

New Zealand

- Good Knowledge of ITIL Service Management Practices
- Good experience in resolving BAU tickets by following SLA. Supported enduser tickets face-to-face, by phone and by using remote application tools.
- Troubleshooting and Identifying the issues involved with administering and maintaining corporate infrastructure, including network connectivity and Internet access.
- Identifying the issues involved in administering and maintaining corporate WAN
- Troubleshooting & software support for PCs running Windows XP and Windows 7, Office 365, handheld devices and Enterprise activation
- Troubleshooting and maintenance of servers
- Hands-on installation of hardware, software upgrades and configuring systems and applications
- User group management & user server migration
- Internal IT audit

- Upkeep of Application suite for email, messaging, Instant Messaging and Mobile devices
- Digital Data management
- Involved in McAfee EEPC 7.0 SS0 security Software upgrade project.
- Administration experience on Checkpoint, McAfee e-policy Orchestrator, NSM, Bluecoat, Print Server and Backup Server.
- Experience in product Procurement.

Vodafone

IT Systems Analyst

March 2012 - January 2014 (1 year 11 months)

New Zealand

- Managed and maintained relationships with SME customers as a single contact
- Provided technical support to customers through phone, email and tickets
- Analysed and troubleshot software and hardware issues
- Helped customers identify and resolve technical problems
- Created help desk documentation with instructions for problem-solving techniques

Education

Avonmore Tertiary Institute

Diploma In Computing- Level 7, System, Networking, and LAN/WAN Management/Manager · (2013 - 2014)

SK University

Master of Electronics, Electrical and Electronics Engineering · (2002 - 2004)